A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Office of Communications, Multimedia material, Accessions 2017:081 and 2017:084 FA1406
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Project Photographs and Foundation-Assigned Photograph Commissions, 1971-2014; 1
  - 1103 Russia Office, 1996; 6 B/W 5x7 photos, negatives (Box 8, Folder 81)
    Photos for 1996 Annual Report - Citizens' Foundation, Moscow Center for Prison Reform, and the Institute for Urban Economics Fund
  - Institute for Urban Economics Photo 1 - Pictures for Annual Report from the Moscow Office, undated; 3 1/2 inch floppy disk (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Institute for Urban Economics Photo 2 - Pictures for Annual Report from Moscow Office, undated; 3 1/2 inch floppy disk (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - Institute for Urban Economics Photo 3 - Pictures for Annual Report from the Moscow Office, undated; 3 1/2 inch floppy disk (Box 8, Folder 81)
  - 1104 Winter 1995 Report, Culture as a Bridge in India - Xeroxes - Photos: Pablo Bartholomew, 1994-1995; 19 color Xeroxes - originals at Gamma Liaison; Includes final version of Ford Foundation Report Winter 1995 (Box 8, Folder 82)
  - 1105 Reception for Dr. Ramphele Mamphele at the Ford Foundation - Photos: Don Pollard, 1997 April 17; Contact sheets and negatives (Box 8, Folder 83)
  - 1106 YouthBuild - Photos: Stella Johnson, 1997 April 30; 10 B/W 4x6 prints, 6 B/W 8x10 prints, 12 contact sheets (Box 8, Folder 84)
    Selection from the Dorchester Youth Collaborative
  - 1108 Meeting of US Foreign Policy: New Relations Abroad, New Voices at Home - Photos: Maria Melin, 1997 March 11; 4 contact sheets, 1 8x10, negatives, booklet: The US Role in the World: New Priorities Abroad and New Voices at Home, Report of the Working Meeting and a Series of Interviews, 1997 (Box 9, Folder 85)
  - 1110 Rural Community College: Uvalde/Eagle Pass/Del Rio - Photos: Jana Birchum, 1997 May 8; 15 B/W 8x10 photos, 10 contact sheets (Box 9, Folder 86)
  - 1111 Hazard Community College, School to Work Program - Photos: J. Breck Smither, 1997 May 16; 1 B/W 8x10. 1 contact sheet, 7 negatives (Box 9, Folder 87)
  - 1112 Ford/Beijing Office - Photos: Anthony Saich, 1997; The Ford Foundation in China booklet and correspondence (Box 9, Folder 88)
  - 1113 YouthBuild - Various Sites - Photos: Martin Dixon, 1997; 21 B/W 8x10 prints with Xeroxes (Box 9, Folder 89)
    Taken at various sites: Austin, TX; St. Louis, MO; York, PA; Philadelphia, PA; Cambridge, MA; New York, NY; Boston, MA
  - 1114 Dr. Huey Perry, Minority Fellowships - Photos: David Rae Morris, 1997 June 25; 2 sets of negatives, 5 B/W prints, 4 contact sheets (Box 9, Folder 90)
  - 1115 Luis Martinez, Minority Doctoral Fellow - Photos: Stella Johnson - Summer 1997 Report (Box 9, Folder 91)
    6 B/W 8x10 prints, 4 contact sheets
  - 1116 1996 Annual Report - Bob Bates, Harvard University; Dance Class at Radcliffe - Photos: Stella Johnson, 1997 February; 20 B/W 5x7, 15 contact sheet (Box 9, Folder 92)
  - 1117 Summer/Fall 1997 - Writers on the Range - Photos: Laurance Aiuppy, 1997 June; Negatives, caption notes, 13 contact sheets, 23 5x7 prints, 4 8x10 prints, newspaper (Box 9, Folder 93)
  - 1118 Summer 1997 Report - Puerto Rico Community Foundation - Photos: Freddy Perojo Igartua, B/W 8x10, B/W 4x6 (Box 10, Folder 94-95)
    Photo subjects: Dr. Ethel Rios Betancourt; Jose Davila School; Cantera Peninsula Development; Producir; Theater Summer Camp; Producir, Cubuy, Puerto Rico; Puerto Rico Community Foundation; Housing Development; CENAD Youth Center
  - 1119 Summer 1997 Report - YouthBuild CEO Dorothy Stoneman - Photos: Andrew Lichtenstein (Box 10, Folder 96)
    8 contact sheets, 10 B/W 8x10 prints
  - 1120 Summer 1997 Report - Director of YouthBuild, Tamara Jones-Short, Sandtown, Baltimore - Photos: Earl Dotter, 13 B/W 8x10 prints, 1 contact sheet (Box 10, Folder 97)
  - 1121 Annual Report 1997 - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) - Campus Diversity Cultural Resources Initiative - Photos: Rob Amberg, 1997 August 9-11; 12 BW 8x10 prints, 6 contact sheets, negatives (Box 10, Folder 98)
    American Festival Cultural Exchange Training and Institute meeting, Lemoyne Owen College, Memphis, TN, August 9-11, 1997
  - 1122 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, Religion (EKR) - Robert C. Maynard Institute for Journalism Education - Photos: Tony Gonzalez, 1997 May 7; 10 B/W 8x10 prints, 5 contact sheets (Box 10, Folder 99)
    Grant no. 950-0257
  - 1123 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, Religion (EKR) - Project GRAD, Houston, Texas - Photos: Tony Gonzalez, 1997 February 24-26; 12 contact sheets, 1 internegative, 30 B/W 8x10 prints (Box 11, Folder 100)
  - 1124 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, Religion (EKR) - National Coalition of Advocates for Students, Orlando, FL - Photos: Tony Gonzalez, 1996-1997; 4 contact sheets, 7 B/W prints (Box 11, Folder 101)
    Grant no. 950-1071-1 - Orange County Public School System students and parents attending the Parent Leadership Council Meeting in Orlando as part of the Multicultural Education Training and Advocacy Program
  - 1124 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, Religion (EKR) - National Coalition of Advocates for Students, Toledo, OH - Photos: Tony Gonzalez, 1997 May 21-23; 8 contact sheets, 12 B/W prints (Box 11, Folder 102)
    In-Service meeting for Partners of the Coalition for Quality Education in Toledo, OH
  - 1125 Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Education, Knowledge, Religion (EKR) - Los Angeles Annenberg Metropolitan Project (Project LAAMP), Pasadena, CA - Photos: Tony Gonzalez, 1997 May 20-31; 7 contact sheets, 12 B/W 8x10 prints (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - 1496 Annual Report 2003 - Godown Arts and Center (The Performing and Visual Arts Centre), Nairobi, Kenya - Photos: Wendy Stone/Corbis, Slides (Box 11, Folder 104)
  - 1340 Annual Report 2000 (Kenya) - Kuona Trust - Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC)/Arts and Culture - Photos: Wendy Stone/Liaison, Slides (Box 11, Folder 105)
  - Uganda - African Women in Business and Politics, 1999; Slides (Box 11, Folder 106)
    Action for Akina Mama WA Africa, African Women's Leadership Institute, Action for Development (ACFODE) Uganda Micro-Credit, Uganda Micro-Credit Scheme, Shangilia MTOTO WA Africa, Rejoice Child of Africa, Susan Berresford, Human Rights Peace Centre (HURIPEC) Makerere University, Kenya Community Development Foundation (KCDF), Uganda Women's Political Cocktail Party
  - Ford Foundation Projects in Uganda - Photos: Wendy Stone, 1990-1991 (Box 11, Folder 107)
  - Iroquois Beading, Samuel Thomas, Cultural Exchange with Kenya - Photos: Wendy Stone, 2005 February; Slides (Box 12, Folder 108)
  - 1443 Annual Report 2001 - Makerere University IFP Fellow: Aaron Mushengyezi, Kampala, Uganda - Photos: Wendy Stone/Liaison/Corbis (Box 12, Folder 109)
  - East African Art and Artists - Naivasha Workshops - Photos: Wendy Stone, undated; Slides (Box 12, Folder 110)
    Captions include: National Museum of Kenya, Art Opening; Artist Sane Wadu in his Studio, Naivasha, Kenya; Nairobi Craft Market; Kuona Trust; Meek Gichugu; Erancis Kahuri; Abusharia; Sudanese Artists; Francis Ngechi; Renaissance of East African Art; Paa Ya Paa Gallery Abusharia; Kojour; Abbkar
  - Small Enterprises Development Authority, Tanzania - Vegetable Markets, Tailors, Industry, Etc. - Photos: Wendy Stone, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 111)
  - Faraja Trust Fund, Tanzania - Education, Community Meetings, Classrooms, Students - Photos: Wendy Stone, 2000 November (Box 12, Folder 112)
  - Mixed Photos by Wendy Stone in Kenya and Uganda, 2000-2001; Slides (Box 12, Folder 113)
    Captions include: Godown Arts; HIV/AIDS; FPPS - Puppets for AIDS Awareness; Kicoshep - Mother/Child HIV/AIDS Testing; LUNGA - CDC; Kicoshep, Kibera Slum, Nairobi, Condom Demonstration Day on World AIDS Day; Straight Talk Uganda; Portfolio - Best Images; Images to Remember; Faraja-Trust - Ex-Sex Workers Now Working in Other Business Selling Dried Fish; Mombosa Tie-Dye Cloth; Faraja Trust Community Education; AIDS; Kenya Kisuktu, Center for Disease Control (CDC) - HIV/AIDS Programs, Youth Education and Research; 1394 Kenya Women's Finance Trust - Assets/Economic Development; Portfolio - Best Images; NGO Work
  - 2001 Annual Report - Maji Naufanisi, Vivid Features, Gaara Dance Foundation, Kuona Trust, Kenya Community Development Fund (KCDF) - Photos: Wendy Stone (Box 12, Folder 114, Box 13, Folder 115)
  - Miscellaneous Kenya Slides - Kenya Society for the Physically Handicapped, Mathare Youth Sports Association, Female Genital Mutilation Education Class (MYSA), Kenya Women's Finance Trust, undated (Box 13, Folder 116)
    Grant no. 990-0488
- Office of Communications - General Photographs, 1962-2015; 2
  - Susan Berresford Photographs, 1
    - Susan V. Berresford, President - Color Photos, Negatives, and Transparencies, 1998 November (Box 13, Folder 117-118)
    - Susan V. Berresford Visiting India Print and Chronicle of Philanthropy, Vol. IX, No. 14, 1997 May 1 (Box 13, Folder 119)
    - Photographer Ben Russell's Photo Commission Agreement - Officer's Headshots, 1996 March-1997 April (Box 16, Folder 193)
      Restricted - confidential material
    - Susan V. Berresford with Vice Presidents and Program Officers - Spring 1998, 1998 February (Box 13, Folder 120)
    - Susan V. Berresford, President, Portraits - Photos: Ben Russell, 1998 November (Box 13, Folder 121-122)
    - 1470 Susan Berresford Official Portrait - Photos: Hazel Hankin, 2002 November 12 (Box 13, Folder 123)
    - Susan V. Berresford Portrait Prints, undated (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Susan Berresford - Shot for NYT US Arts Folio 646-234-9611, 2006 September; CDR (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - "Evocative" Photos - Photos Related to SVB Video, undated; DVDRW (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Susan Berresford - Asst'd Binder Images (jpegs) Ford Fdn (red marker, Sony disk), undated; CDR (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Susan Berresford - Asst'd Binder Images (jpegs) Ford Foundation (blue marker, Office Depot disk), undated; CDR (Box 14, Folder 124)
    - Susan V. Berresford Identified Photos - Prints and Photocopies with Captions, 1982-2006 (Box 14, Folder 125)
  - Vice President Photographs, 2
    - Melvin Oliver/Harcourt Brace, 1997 (Box 14, Folder 126)
    - Alison Bernstein, Vice President - Photos: Ben Russell, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 127)
    - Barry Gaberman, Senior Vice President, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 128)
    - Melvin Oliver, Vice President, Neighborhoods, Families, and Livelihoods - Photos: Porter Gifford/Gamma Liaison, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 129)
      Original folder says, "Do Not Use"
    - Bradford Smith, Vice President, Peace Equity and Governance - Photos: Porter Gifford/Gamma Liaison, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 130)
    - Robert Curvin, Vice President for Communications - Photos: Chester Higgins, Jr., All Rights Reserved, undated (Box 14, Folder 131)
    - Do Not Use - Robert Curvin, Vice President - Photos: Porter Gifford/Gamma Liaison, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 132)
    - Linda Strumpf, Vice President - Photos: Ben Russell, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 133)
    - Barron Tenny, Executive Vice President - Photos: Porter Gifford/Gamma Liaison, 1996 March (Box 14, Folder 134)
    - Alex Wilde, Vice President, Communications - Photos: Victor Greene Studios, 2000 February 1 (Box 15, Folder 135)
    - Ford Foundation Negatives - 960313, 1-11, 11 - Photos: Ben Russell, undated (Box 15, Folder 136)
  - Staff Photographs, 3
    - Bradford K. Smith, undated (Box 15, Folder 137)
    - Walter Coward, undated (Box 15, Folder 138)
    - Roland Anglin, undated (Box 15, Folder 139)
    - Margaret Hempel, 1992 June (Box 15, Folder 140)
    - Mahnaz Ispahani, undated (Box 15, Folder 141)
    - Jan Jaffe - Photos: Ben Russell, 1996 March (Box 15, Folder 142)
    - Michael Lipsky, undated (Box 15, Folder 143)
    - Mary Mcclymont, undated (Box 15, Folder 144)
    - Lisa Mensah, undated (Box 15, Folder 145)
    - Ronald Mincy, Senior Program Officer, undated (Box 15, Folder 146)
    - Helen Neuborne, Program Officer, Rights and Social Justice Program, undated (Box 15, Folder 147)
    - Mrs. Sadako Ogata, undated (Box 15, Folder 148)
    - Janice Petrovich, undated (Box 15, Folder 149)
    - Marcia Smith, 1993 April (Box 15, Folder 150)
    - Christine Vincent, undated (Box 15, Folder 151)
    - Christine Vincent, Deputy Director, Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC) - Photos: Kerry Rae, Victor Greene Studio, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 152)
    - Steven Zwerling, undated (Box 15, Folder 153)
    - June Zeitlin, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 154)
    - Marcy H. Cady, Consultant for Education, Media, Arts, and Culture (EMAC), Photos: Kerry Rae, Victor Greene Studio, 2000 (Box 15, Folder 155)
  - Building and Garden Photographs, 4
    - Ford Foundation Building Slides and Duplicates, 1988 September (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - X-Mas 2008, W. Fawbush, Ford Foundation Building, CD-R (Box 15, Folder 156)
    - Ford Foundation Building Photos, 1967, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 157)
    - Ford Foundation Building and Garden - Originals and Contact Sheets, 1990 (Box 15, Folder 158)
    - 1990 Photos of Ford Foundation Building - Photos: Richard Bereholtz (Box 15, Folder 159)
    - Ford Foundation Garden - Photos: Ezra Stoller, 1967 (Box 15, Folder 160)
    - Negatives - Atrium Photo Made for Jonathon Green, 1997 October 15 (Box 15, Folder 161)
  - Trustees Photographs, 5
    - Kathryn S. Fuller, Trustee, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - K. Fuller Photo Shoot - Folio 646.234.9611, 2006; CD-R (Box 15, Folder 162)
    - Paul A. Allaire, Chair, Board of Trustees (Laura Bush and Gray Davis), undated (Box 15, Folder 163)
    - Alain J. P. Belda, New Board Member, 1999 December (Box 15, Folder 164)
    - Anke A. Ehrhardt, 1999 (Box 16, Folder 165)
    - Robert D. Haas, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 166)
    - Sir Christopher Hogg, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 167)
    - Vernon E. Jordan, Jr., Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 168)
    - Yolanda Kakabadse, Board of Trustee, 2000 May 2 (Box 16, Folder 169)
    - David T. Kearns, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 170)
    - Wilma P. Mankiller, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 171)
    - Richard Moe, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 172)
    - Yolanda J. Moses, Trustee, President of the American Association for Higher Education, undated (Box 16, Folder 173)
    - Luis G. Nogales, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 174)
    - General Olusegun Obasanjo, Trustee, 1998 September 28 (Box 16, Folder 175)
      General Obasanjo addressing the Trustees at the Ford Foundation, Photos: Martin Dixon; Trustee 11/88
    - Deval Patrick, undated (Box 16, Folder 176)
    - Dorothy Sattes Ridings, undated (Box 16, Folder 177)
    - Henry B. Schnacht, Trustee, 1986 October (Box 16, Folder 178)
    - Monkombu S. Swaminathan, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 179)
    - Ratan N. Tata, Trustee, undated (Box 16, Folder 180)
    - Carl Weisbrod, Trustee, President of Alliance for Downtown NY, Inc., undated (Box 16, Folder 181)
    - W. Richard West, New Board Member, 1999 April (Box 16, Folder 182)
    - Juliet V. Garcia, Trustee, 2003 June (Box 16, Folder 183)
  - Filler Photographs, 6
    - Administrative Intern Job #490 Negatives, undated (Box 16, Folder 184)
    - Official White House Photo, Al Gore to Susan Berresford, 1997 October 8 (Box 16, Folder 185)
    - Women's Programming and Child Survival Meeting, Ford Foundation, New Delhi, 1982 April 23 (Box 16, Folder 186)
    - 2015 Leadership Photo and Photo Key (Box 16, Folder 187)
    - 2014 Leadership Photo Key (Box 16, Folder 188)
    - Olusegun Obasanjo, Ford Foundation After Release from Prison, undated (Box 16, Folder 189)
    - Al Gore and Susan Berresford, 1997 (Box 16, Folder 190)
    - Kofi Annan, undated (Box 16, Folder 191)
    - 1312 New Directions, New Donors - Ford Foundation Arts Initiative - Photos: Stephanie Berger, 2000 May 10 (Box 16, Folder 192)
    - 2014 Leadership Photo (Box 17, Folder 195)
    - …And Justice For All - Package #48; Courtroom Sketches, undated (Box 17, Folder 196)
      71 4536-001 - sent to Mrs. Eleanor Belich
    - Job #1271 - Public Affairs "Page 5" #15, undated (Box 17, Folder 197)
    - Job #1271 Artwork "Page IV" (frontispiece), 1962 (Box 17, Folder 198)
    - Job #1371 - Annual Report 1967 (Box 17, Folder 199)
      7 oversized photographs labelled "Art Work"
    - Job #64729 Annual Report 1966 (Box 17, Folder 200)
      3 oversize photographs - p. 46 and p. 27